Chris Philbin

chris@chrisphilbin.net
github.com/ChrisPhilbin

(732) - 757 - 1625

chrisphilbin.net

Warminster, PA

linkedin.com/in/chris-philbin

Motivated and driven developer with experience in various languages and building apps from the ground up. Specializes in Javascript, React/Redux, Vue and Rails. Professional strengths include problem solving, written and verbal communication, time management, teamwork, and accountability. Results-driven mindset from 7+ years of experience in the HCM SaaS space.

2019

2012

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, New York, NY
Software development
•
DeSales University, Center Valley, PA B.A., Business Management

SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Languages: Javascript, HTML, CSS, Ruby,
Python, SQL
Technologies: React/Redux, Vue, Node.js,
Express, Tailwind CSS, Material-UI, Bootstrap,
Webpack, REST APIs, Git, Linux, Ruby on Rails,
MVC Design Pattern, NPM, Docker, Google
Cloud Platform, WordPress

EXPERIENCE

Coastal Coating

Full stack developer/contractor

Fully Remote September 2021 - Current

- Develop & maintain a public-facing website for the business.
- Collaborate with owner to provide updates on agreed upon enhancements to the site.
- Build & maintain mobile-first front end using Vue and TailwindCSS.
- Develop & maintain backend using Node.js and nodemailer to handle appointment requests.
- Deploy to Google Cloud Platform and Google Cloud Functions.
- Adhere to SEO best practices when developing an SPA.

Ultimate Kronos Group

Fully Remote

Sr. Business Development Representative

June 2016 - Current

- Responsible for the generation of qualified customers for a team of outside sales representatives.
- Achieved 121% of quota in FY2017, 150% of quota in FY2018, 120% of quota in 2019.
- Found north of \$7 million in new business for the sales organization.
- Develop weekly technology training segments to communicate industry news to peers.
- Train and mentor new teammates which led to several promotions of those mentored.

Allentown, PA

Inside Sales Representative

- Analyzed the human capital needs, processes, and technology to position ADP's cost-effective solutions.
- Managed sales processes exceeding sales quota both fiscal years (2015: 118%, 2016: 120%).
- Developed C-level relationships and partnered with sales to ignite change within Human Capital Management.
- Participated in Local Engagement And Diversity committee responsible for giving back to the community.

Jamren, Inc Quakertown, PA
General Manager May 2009 - May 2014

- Full ownership of P&L statement for \$3.5million in annual cash flow.
- Conducted annual and bi-annual performance reviews and wage reviews on employees and managers.
- Facilitated regional marketing plan, as well as local store marketing tactics to increase revenue.
- Implemented new hierarchy of organizing managers and employees to meet new demands imposed by sales trends; now present in over 20,000 locations.

SIDE PROJECTS

Does Rover Live | Github | Demo

Vue app that collects crowd sourced information informing users whether or not the dog in a movie lives. Uses Vue/Vuex on the front end along with Tailwind CSS for styling and a NodeJS/Express backend using Google Cloud Functions.

Interactive World Map | Github | Demo

Vue app introducing interactivity into a world map SVG in order to interface predefined regions fetched via an external API. Mobile responsive and styled using Tailwind CSS.

Reply All Generator | Github | Demo

React front end utilizing a Node backend via Firebase/Google Cloud Functions for the API/back end. Allows authenticated users to create and save email replies and then randomly select those replies based on how much personality is desired based on what the user desires.